Let's look at a few different ways we might approach styling our React Native components.
我们来看看设置 React Native 组件样式的几种方式
So the first one and the obvious one is we can
第一种 也是最明显的方式是
pass inline styles to any component that we want.
向任何组件传入内嵌样式
So both to our view component as well as our text component.
向 View 组件和 Text 组件传入样式
And then, what we can do is style takes in an object.
然后向其中传入一个对象
So what we can say here is come in here and say flex: 1,
在这里输入 flex: 1
will say marginLeft: 10,
然后输入 marginLeft: 10
marginRight: 10, alignItems: 'center' and then, justifyContent: 'center'.
marginRight: 10, alignItems: 'center’, justifyContent: 'center'
And then, what we can do here is we can just say, color: 'red'.
然后在这里输入 color: 'red'
All right, so this looks pretty good if we go to our app,
看起来正常 回到应用界面
you'll notice that we get those styles but something feels a little bit off here.
你会看到这些样式 但是这里有点奇怪
Inline styling is fine with React Native because
对于 React Native 来说 可以内嵌样式
styles are kind of coupled to the component regardless but,
因为样式与组件进行组合
it feels a little weird to have all of these styles just inline like this.
但是这样内嵌所有这些样式有点奇怪
So what we can do is what if we came in here and really just moved these out out of here.
我们可以将这些样式移出来并放在这里
So let's say, container,
输入 container
it's going to be that.
然后是这些样式
And then, what we can do is we can say,
然后输入 text:
text, is going to be this.
将是这些样式
And then now, we can do something like this.
然后输入这些内容
And then, we can also do something like that,
还可以输入这些内容
where we now have the same styles applied to our components.
我们为组件应用了相同的样式
But now, they're living in an object,
但是现在这些样式位于对象中了
and if we format this properly,
调整下样式
it's going to look a lot more reasonable because we're not inlining everything,
看起来更合理了 因为我们没有内嵌所有样式
even though we're getting the same effect.
虽然效果是一样的
Now, this is actually a pretty good approach to
这实际上是对 React Native 组件
styling components and to styling React Native components.
进行样式设置的很好方式
So good, in fact, that React Native has something similar built in.
实际上 React Native 内置了类似的功能
So what we can do is there the style sheet method here.
我们可以导入这个 StyleSheet 方法
And instead of just having this be a raw object,
不再将这些设为原始对象
what we can do is we can say,
而是输入 StyleSheet.create
StyleSheet.creates and then, we can pass it an object.
然后向其传入一个对象
And then now, it's going to be the exact same as we had above.
效果和上面的一样
But now what React Native is going to do is it's going to optimize
但现在 React Native 将稍微优化这些样式
the styles a little bit and give us a little bit of a performance boost.
并帮助我们提升性能
So whenever you are using styles with React Native what I like to do,
每当你在 React Native 中设置样式时
if it's really more than just one or two properties on the components itself as a style,
如果是多个组件样式
I'll go ahead and create a StyleSheet and move it down here.
我喜欢创建一个 StyleSheet 并移到下面
So in this case, what I would really do is I would probably just do something
在这种情况下 我会输入这些内容
like this because I don't like to think of names.
因为我不喜欢记住名称
And so this text,
这个文本的颜色将为红色
it's going to have a color of red but because we have all of these styles here,
但是我们在这里设定了这些样式
we'll go ahead and use StyleSheet.create to
因此将使用 StyleSheet.create
create that StyleSheet and then just apply the styles with styles.
创建该 StyleSheet 然后使用
whatever the property name is,
styles.（属性名称）应用这些样式
in this case, container.
这里属性名称是 container